<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Authors on EDgility for School</title>
    <link>www.edgility.school/team/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Authors on EDgility for School</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Nov 2018 10:47:58 +1000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="www.edgility.school/team/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Paul Magnuson, Phd.</title>
      <link>www.edgility.school/team/pmagnuson/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Nov 2018 10:47:58 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>www.edgility.school/team/pmagnuson/</guid>
      <description>Teacher, Researcher, Writer
Currently works at Leysin American School in Switzerland (LAS)
Full Bio
We can do school better by supporting authentic learning.
I hold a PhD in Curriculum &amp;amp; Instruction from the University of Minnesota, a ScrumMaster certification in Agility, and a belief that we all can build on our current practice to create incredible learning organizations.
I attribute much of my innovation in teaching and learning to 20 years of summer camp experience.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bill Tihen</title>
      <link>www.edgility.school/team/btihen/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Nov 2018 10:47:58 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>www.edgility.school/team/btihen/</guid>
      <description>On a quest to explore and uplift.
Currently working at GaraioREM as a Developer
Full Bio
I hold a Masters in Electrical Engineering and worked as a robotist and researcher. Then I moved into teaching (Math, Computer Science and Physics). Overtime I also worked in IT at schools. Most recently, I have moved into full-time Software Development and also aquired a ScrumMaster certificate.
My technical background has strongly influenced how I teach: research and Agile practices have helped me develop a keen interest in the joy of exploring or ‘playful experiments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nicole Cosgrove</title>
      <link>www.edgility.school/team/ncosgrove/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Nov 2018 10:47:58 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>www.edgility.school/team/ncosgrove/</guid>
      <description>Currently works at Leysin American School in Switzerland (LAS)
Full Bio
As a teacher in the UK, I started my career working in diverse and somewhat challenging public schools. I began to question my role as a teacher. Was I really doing it right? Why did I feel like giving up? It was a weird feeling and I didn&amp;rsquo;t feel like my students were getting the best from me.
Moving to the Alps and teaching here has given me a whole new perspective, not just because of the amazing views, but due to the freedom and professional push my colleagues have given.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dan Patton</title>
      <link>www.edgility.school/team/dpatton/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Nov 2018 10:47:58 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>www.edgility.school/team/dpatton/</guid>
      <description>Dan worked at LAS as a science teacher. His interest included plant biology, and sustainable living. He also explored robotics and remote sensing with Bill.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
