<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on EDgility for School</title>
    <link>www.edgility.school/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on EDgility for School</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 Nov 2018 15:15:34 +1000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="www.edgility.school/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Paul Magnuson, Phd.</title>
      <link>www.edgility.school/team/pmagnuson/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Nov 2018 10:47:58 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>www.edgility.school/team/pmagnuson/</guid>
      <description>Teacher, Researcher, Writer
Currently works at Leysin American School in Switzerland (LAS)
Full Bio
We can do school better by supporting authentic learning.
I hold a PhD in Curriculum &amp;amp; Instruction from the University of Minnesota, a ScrumMaster certification in Agility, and a belief that we all can build on our current practice to create incredible learning organizations.
I attribute much of my innovation in teaching and learning to 20 years of summer camp experience.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Values</title>
      <link>www.edgility.school/edgility_v1_0_0/values/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Nov 2018 12:33:46 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>www.edgility.school/edgility_v1_0_0/values/</guid>
      <description>The four values define core mindset we are working toward:
 EXPLORATION - Exploration and play over tests and perfection; GROWTH - Growth and rework over assessment reports without corresponding mechanisms to improve identified weaknesses; SELF-REGULATION - Student-driven reflection and improvement over teacher directives; and LIFE WORTHY LEARNING - Learning that supports additional learning over detailed course content.  We understand that there is value in many approaches and we don&amp;rsquo;t exclude other values, we just prioritize these over others.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Practices</title>
      <link>www.edgility.school/edgility_v1_0_0/practices/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Nov 2018 15:15:34 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>www.edgility.school/edgility_v1_0_0/practices/</guid>
      <description>Here are the following ten practices that we find that help students with engagement and self-regulation:
 EXPLORATION - Exploration over fixed content GROWTH MINDSET - Growth over stasis TRUST - Self-regulation over teacher control TRANSPARENCY - Visibility over obscurity ADAPTABILITY - Flexibility over rigidity SMALLIFY - Quick, workable iterations and feedback over big plans VALUE - Valuable learning over convenient assessments COLLABORATION - Working together over competing against REDO - Reflection and progress over right and done UPLIFT - Problems as opportunity over problems as problems  Each author of this document implements these differently in the classroom, but as practices we all agree they are helpful.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bill Tihen</title>
      <link>www.edgility.school/team/btihen/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Nov 2018 10:47:58 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>www.edgility.school/team/btihen/</guid>
      <description>On a quest to explore and uplift.
Currently working at GaraioREM as a Developer
Full Bio
I hold a Masters in Electrical Engineering and worked as a robotist and researcher. Then I moved into teaching (Math, Computer Science and Physics). Overtime I also worked in IT at schools. Most recently, I have moved into full-time Software Development and also aquired a ScrumMaster certificate.
My technical background has strongly influenced how I teach: research and Agile practices have helped me develop a keen interest in the joy of exploring or ‘playful experiments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nicole Cosgrove</title>
      <link>www.edgility.school/team/ncosgrove/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Nov 2018 10:47:58 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>www.edgility.school/team/ncosgrove/</guid>
      <description>Currently works at Leysin American School in Switzerland (LAS)
Full Bio
As a teacher in the UK, I started my career working in diverse and somewhat challenging public schools. I began to question my role as a teacher. Was I really doing it right? Why did I feel like giving up? It was a weird feeling and I didn&amp;rsquo;t feel like my students were getting the best from me.
Moving to the Alps and teaching here has given me a whole new perspective, not just because of the amazing views, but due to the freedom and professional push my colleagues have given.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dan Patton</title>
      <link>www.edgility.school/team/dpatton/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Nov 2018 10:47:58 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>www.edgility.school/team/dpatton/</guid>
      <description>Dan worked at LAS as a science teacher. His interest included plant biology, and sustainable living. He also explored robotics and remote sensing with Bill.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Change Candidates</title>
      <link>www.edgility.school/edgility_v1_0_0/change_candidates/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Nov 2018 15:15:34 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>www.edgility.school/edgility_v1_0_0/change_candidates/</guid>
      <description>We aren’t finished, we’re just beginning. We are interested in collecting more updating EDgility.
Of course, as educators, we will keep our own priorities.
Published Additional Practices  Slack Choice  Author&amp;rsquo;s Additional Practices  Retrospectives Engagement - Hero&amp;rsquo;s Journey Feedback - Natural and Pixar Style Context - learning toward student chosen goal - within the context of the class  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>www.edgility.school/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2018 17:01:34 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>www.edgility.school/contact/</guid>
      <description>We understand there are many ways to engage with education and EDgility &amp;ndash; if you would like to see how we the authors engage with EDgility you can see https://www.peakchallenges.ch and http://www.agileinthealps.com/</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Origin</title>
      <link>www.edgility.school/origin/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2018 17:01:34 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>www.edgility.school/origin/</guid>
      <description>We are long-time educators. Combined we have over 30 years of academic experience.
We meet at Leysin American School (LAS). We felt drawn to take education to the next level &amp;ndash; in particular to encourage students to feel good about themselves, have enthusiasm for school and learning and to take their own initiative to be life-long learners.
In this way, we felt we were cultivating young adults who will be able to thrive and enjoy the future, its challenges and changing nature.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
